COLIN GROARK

WEB DEVELOPER

Full-stack web developer with experience building responsive websites and developing efficient systems and tools in the private and non-profit sectors. I have a firm grasp on Git version control, RESTful APIs, and technologies from React and JavaScript to PostgreSQL and Node. Prior to engineering, I worked for consulting firms and non-profits where I garnered experience managing programs, teams, budgets and business development processes.

SKILLS

Front End Web Development: React,

JavaScript, JQuery, ES6, CSS3, HTML5, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, Recharts

Back End Web Development: Node.js,

PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Python, MongoDB

Technology: RESTful API,

Heroku Cloud Platform, Git Workflow, GitHub

Languages: Advanced Spanish, Beginning Swahili and Japanese

CONTACT

- www.colingroark.com
- **♀** Seattle, Washington

in colin-groark/

n cgroark

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Training 2018

University of Washington, Evans School of Public Policy and Governance MPA: Environmental Policy and Natural Resource Management

Certificate: Environmental Management

Trinity College

BA: International Studies, Hispanic Studies

VOLUNTEERING

Seattle Public Utilities: Solid Waste Advisory
Committee
Committee
Committee
Committee
Committee
Committee

Committee Member Nov 2016 to Current

Tilth Alliance Seattle
Master Composter/Soil Builder Apr 2016 to
Volunteer Current

RECENT WORK

Node.js/Express: Carbon Commuter

Track, log and chart carbon emissions of trips travelled based on distance and mode of transport

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Google Maps API, Chart.js, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Data visualizations for distance ratios and carbon emissions using Chart.js JavaScript library
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://carbon-commute.herokuapp.com/

React/MongoDB: HouseHub

Create a house profile with roommates. Assign and track chores, house bills, and pantry items, and post memos

- Technologies: React, MongoDB, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://tpcc.herokuapp.com/

Node.js/Express: Get Out There

Search for National Parks by state, save your favorite parks, see location and real-time weather forecast

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- RESTful APIs: National Park Service, Google Maps, Weather Underground
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://get-out-there-parksweather.herokuapp.com/

Front end game: Sort It

Race a timer and score points when sorting trash, compostables and recyclables correctly

- · Technologies: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS
- Deployed on GitHub pages: https://cgroark.github.io/game-waste/

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Full-Stack Web Development Student

Seattle, Washington Nov 2017 to Feb 2018

- 12-week immersive full-stack web development training with 480 hours of instruction
- Built responsive user-focused projects drawing on technologies that include React, Express, MongoDB, Node js,
 PostreSQL, JQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and front-end libraries and frameworks such as Materialize, Bootstrap,
 CSS Grid, Recharts and Chart.js
- Established firm grasp of RESTful API architecture, Heroku cloud platform, Git and GitHub version control, database structure and modeling, and emerging web development trends
- Worked with cross-functional teams of developers and UX designers to bring week-long and quick turnaround projects to fruition

Tilth Alliance (Seattle Tilth)

Director, Community Education and Environmental Programs

Seattle, Washington Aug 2015 to Nov 2017

- Oversaw Tilth Alliance outreach and education programs on resource conservation and stewardship
- Managed 11 person team and \$890K grant and contract portfolio funding seven core programs
- Developed processes to track program deliverables, grant applications and reporting
- Built budget tracking systems in Excel to monitor program expenditures; and SharePoint metrics tracker to monitor program impact
- Led proposal strategy and client interview to secure 5-year \$2.2 million resource conservation contract with Seattle Public Utilities

Envirolssues

Seattle, Washingotn Apr 2013 to Aug 2015

Business Development Associate

- Managed business development and marketing team for community outreach consulting firm
- Led proposal teams and supported strategy and content to compete for public projects
- Created metrics dashboard and data analysis tools to better assess proposal trends and outcomes

Basel Action Network

Research Intern

Seattle, Washington Apr 2012 to Mar 2013

- Conducted research and drafted reports on the illegal trafficking of electronic waste
- Developed data calculator for app to measure environmental benefits of recycling electronics

Management Systems International

Washington, DC Sep 2009 to Sep 2011, Aug 2007 to Aug 2009

Business Development Associate and Consultant

Sep 2009 to Sep 2011. Aug 20

Coordinated proposal towns to compete for foreign aid projects up to \$21 million across sowen sectors.

- Coordinated proposal teams to compete for foreign aid projects up to \$21million across seven sectors
 Managed teams to capture technical proposal components within strict deadlines
- Provided budgetary, recruitment and report-writing support for complex international aid contracts